[{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"1. The reuptake of these molecules is inhibited by AM404, a metabolite of acetaminophen. The activation of a type of receptor for these molecules causes depolarization-induced suppression of inhibition. In 2018, the FDA approved the use of one of these molecules called Epidiolex to treat Lennox–Gastaut (“LEN-ux gas-TOH”) syndrome and Dravet (“dra-VAY”) syndrome. Raphael Mechoulam (“meh-shoo-LOM”) performed a total synthesis of one of these molecules and discovered 2-arachidonoylglycerol (“2-uh-RACK-id-on-oil-glycerol”) and anandamide, which are endogenously produced examples of these molecules that bind to the CB1 and CB2 receptors. A diol member of this class of molecules is non-psychoactive and often administered in the form of an oil. For 10 points, name this group of molecules, one of which is responsible for the psychoactive effects of marijuana. ","answer":"ANSWER: cannabinoids [or endocannabinoids; or phytocannabinoids; prompt on THC or tetrahydrocannabinol or CBD or cannabidiol by asking “what class of molecules does that belong to?”; prompt on CB1 or CB2 receptor] <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"2. This practice “in miniature” titles a Laurie Patton essay arguing for etymological religious scholarship, in response to an essay titled for this practice that critiques “Pan-Babylonian” comparisons, by Jonathan Z. Smith. The Mithras Liturgy and other Hellenized Greek Papyri instruct readers in this practice, which modifies a “garden” in Max Weber’s (“VAY-bur’s”) vision of the pre-modern world. A “sacred” version of this practice was outlined in The Book of Abramelin, an influential grimoire (“grim-WAHR”). In Acts, a Gnostic leader wows people with this practice before Peter converts him. The Samaritan Simon mastered this practice, which a woman from Endor uses to summon Samuel for Saul. This belief is a precursor of religion according to The Golden Bough (“bao”). For 10 points, name this practice persecuted by witch trials. ","answer":"ANSWER: magic [or sorcery or enchantment; accept witchcraft or the Witch of Endor; accept the occult or divination or necromancy; prompt on supernatural; accept Simon Magus; accept Greek Magical Papyri; prompt on flying or levitation by asking “what power let Simon fly?”] (The Jonathan Smith essay is “In Comparison a Magic Still Dwells.”) <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"3. In this artwork, the odd shift of a robe’s hue from green to yellow exemplifies the cangiantismo (“kahn-jahn-TEEZ-mo”) technique. That detail has been used to argue that the restoration of this artwork in the 1980s destroyed a wash of glue and carbon black. In this artwork, garlands of oak and bronze medallions frame the image of a bearded figure reaching his hands into clouds. A sonnet by its artist claims that creating this artwork “jammed [his] belly under [his] chin” and gave him a goiter. A muscular woman turns to lift a giant book in this artwork’s depiction of the Libyan Sibyl. Twenty male ignudi (“een-YOO-dee”) appear in this artwork, which includes The Separation of Light from Darkness and a painting centered on two outstretched fingers. For 10 points, The Creation of Adam is part of what set of frescoes by Michelangelo? ","answer":"ANSWER: Sistine Chapel ceiling [or Volta della Cappella Sistina; prompt on the Sistine Chapel; anti-prompt on The Separation of Light From Darkness until “Separation” is read by asking “can you be less specific?”] <Painting/Sculpture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"4. A character in a poem by this author remarks how he may “seem more bitter to your taste / Than herb Sardinian, rougher than the broom, / More worthless than strewn sea-weed.” Gavin Douglas’s full vernacular translation of a poem by this author was praised by Robert Fitzgerald in an essay centering on John Dryden’s landmark translation of it. The line “love conquers all; let us, too, yield to love” appears in the last poem of a collection by this author that borrowed its structure from Theocritus’s Idylls (“idles”). A poem by this author that praises Gaius Asinius Pollio has been theorized to concern Jesus Christ due to its mention of a “great progeny of Jove.” An epic poem by this author opens with the line “I sing of arms and the man.” For 10 points, name this poet of the Eclogues and the Aeneid. ","answer":"ANSWER: Virgil [or Publius Vergilius Maro] <World/Other Literature> 5. “Wanton addicts” with no second-order desires cease to be people and lose this status according to a paper that presents the “hierarchical mesh model.” Susan Wolf argued that having this status is the same as having the ability to do what one thinks is right, in a book titled for this “within Reason.” Robert Kane is among the philosophers who endorse the libertarian view on this status, which he explores in a book he titled for this status “and Values.” “Reactive attitudes” are presented in a P. F. Strawson essay whose title pairs this status with resentment. Frankfurt cases challenge the view that moral responsibility requires this status. The position of compatibilism states that this status is compatible with determinism. For 10 points, name this status in which one has control over their actions. "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"6. A member of this group named George Maynard brought a compelled speech case to the Supreme Court after covering the “Live Free or Die” motto on his New Hampshire license plate. The Court ruled that the First Amendment did not cover “fighting words” in Chaplinsky v. New Hampshire after a member of this organization who distributed pamphlets called a cop a “racketeer.” Members of this group were the plaintiffs in West Virginia v. Barnette, which reversed an earlier decision that upheld the expulsion of the Gobitis children for their refusal to salute the flag. A 2009 Canadian court case over children’s legal competence arose out of this sect’s refusal to accept blood transfusions. For 10 points, name this Christian denomination that publishes The Watchtower and meets in Kingdom Halls. ","answer":"ANSWER: Jehovah’s Witnesses [prompt on JW; prompt on Christians or Protestants by asking “of what denomination?”] <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"7. In X-ray crystallography, the X-rays can cause these phenomena, forming a namesake field that can be investigated to resolve the phase problem. The closeness of the load impedance to the characteristic impedance (“im-PEE-dense”) in transmission lines can be evaluated by using a ratio named for these phenomena, which is the ratio of the maximum to minimum AC voltages, as impedance mismatch causes these phenomena. Microwave cavities create these phenomena in the cavity’s interior at its resonant frequency. In one dimension, these phenomena arise from the superposition of two waves with the same frequency and amplitude and opposite propagation velocities, which can result from reflection of a travelling wave at the end of the medium. For 10 points, name these phenomena whose nodes and antinodes do not move in space, often demonstrated via shaking a toy slinky or jump rope. ","answer":"ANSWER: standing waves [or stationary waves; accept X-ray standing waves or X-ray standing wave field; accept (voltage) standing wave ratio; “wave” is not needed after read; prompt on waves until read] <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"8. A 2017 opera with a name inspired by an earlier opera by this composer draws on the letters of Louise Clappe and the newspaper articles of Mark Twain and is the most recent opera by John Adams. After writing the song “Avalon,” Al Jolson was sued by this composer’s publisher, who claimed that the song plagiarized a B minor tenor aria by this composer that opens with a clarinet solo. An opera by this composer includes a tenor aria, “Ch’ella mi creda,” sung by the bandit Dick Johnson, who asks a crowd not to mention his fate to Minnie. The aria “E lucevan le stelle” (“ay loo-CHAY-von lay stell-ay”) is sung by Caravadossi to the title diva of another opera by this composer, who herself sings “Vissi d’arte” while being manipulated by Baron Scarpia. For 10 points, name this composer of The Girl of the Golden West and Tosca. ","answer":"ANSWER: Giacomo Puccini <Other Arts (Opera)> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"9. After two characters in this play make wishes on the rising moon, one reveals that she asked for “success and happiness for my precious children.” A character in this play autographs a program of a high school production of The Pirates of Penzance in a scene that’s lit by candlelight, since another character paid for a membership in the Union of Merchant Seamen instead of the light bill. In this play, a shoe warehouse worker nicknamed “Shakespeare” warns that this play will be “sentimental… and not realistic” as “memory takes a lot of poetic licence.” At the end of this play, a character nicknamed “Blue Roses” is told to “blow out the candles” by Tom. For 10 points, the “gentleman caller” Jim accidentally breaks a unicorn from the title collection of Laura Wingfield’s figurines in what Tennessee Williams play? ","answer":"ANSWER: The Glass Menagerie <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"0. Rafaela Herrera defended this country’s pirate-proof Fortress of the Immaculate Conception. Shipwrecked slaves and the Mayangna formed this country’s Sambu people. A [emphasize] neighboring country’s national hero Juan Santamaría set fire to a hotel in this country during the Second Battle of Rivas. The Puritan Providence Island Company colonized an island off this country’s east coast and established relations with a tortoiseshell-trading kingdom around this country’s city of Bluefields. Cornelius Vanderbilt opposed an American filibustering expedition to this country that briefly resulted in its rule by William Walker. In 1894, this country annexed the Mosquito Coast. For 10 points, name this country where the Contras fought the Sandinistas. ","answer":"ANSWER: Nicaragua <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"1. A book by Alison Dagnes (“DAG-niss”) uses social networks to explain why liberals are more successful at deploying this phenomenon than conservatives. In his book titled the “anatomy of” this concept, Arthur Asa Berger outlined 45 logical mechanisms that lead to the generation of this thing, which Victor Raskin claimed is generated linguistically through script opposition. In communications theory, non-bona-fide communication tends to evoke this phenomenon. Theories of this phenomenon include the benign violation theory and relief theory. Henri Bergson’s writing on this phenomenon focuses on incongruous juxtaposition. The superiority and inferiority theories of this phenomenon respectively rely on ridicule and self-deprecation. For 10 points, name this social phenomenon that may elicit laughter. ","answer":"ANSWER: humor [accept comedy; accept laughter until read; accept any descriptive answer indicating making something funny or humorous; accept jokes or joking; accept the comic; accept sarcasm; prompt on irony] (The Alison Dagnes book is A Conservative Walks Into a Bar.) <Social Science (Sociology and Other)> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"2. In a piece titled for these figures, the short sixth movement, Pavana Lachrymae, quotes the chorale from Franz Schubert’s “Death and the Maiden,” then fades away. The highest note sung in the documented history of the Met was in a performance of a 2016 opera titled for one of these figures by Thomas Adès (“ADD-iss”). A movement called Threnody I: Night of the Electric Insects opens a piece for “electric string quartet” titled for these figures. A bass aria sung by one of these figures “of Agony” appears in Edward Elgar’s The Dream of Gerontius. The first movement of Paul Hindemith’s Mathis der Maler (“MAH-tiss dare MAH-lur”) symphony is titled for a “concert” of these beings. George Crumb’s string quartet is titled for “Black” ones. For 10 points, Alban Berg’s (“ALL-bahn BAIRG’s”) Violin Concerto is dedicated “to the memory of” what kind of holy being? ","answer":"ANSWER: angels [accept Black Angels; accept The Exterminating Angel; accept Angel of (the) Agony; accept “Engelkonzert” or “Angelic Concert”] <Classical Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"3. B. W. Silverman showed that if a set of values are assumed to have this property, then the optimal bandwidth for kernel density estimation depends on the number of values to the negative one-fifth power. Subpopulations with this property are represented by the most common “mixture model” for clustering data. The Box–Cox transformation outputs a set of values with this property, which can be verified using the Shapiro–Wilk test. Like independence, this property is assumed to hold for the data [emphasize] within groups before performing ANOVA. Sample means that are repeatedly taken from any distribution will collectively have this property, according to the central limit theorem. For 10 points, the “68–95–99.7” rule can only be used if the data have what property, meaning they approximate a “bell curve”? ","answer":"ANSWER: normality [or normally distributed; accept conforming to or approximating a normal distribution or Gaussian distribution; prompt on bell curve or bell-shaped curve; do not accept or prompt on “normalized”] <Other Science (Math)> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"4. In a story by this author set on “the eve of the August Bank Holiday,” a character “whose words were almost confined” to “Yes” and “No” remarks “Wren built that house, father says.” After meeting Granger and an economic attaché, a character created by this author tries to go to the House of the Five Hundred Girls. In a story by this author, the Wormsley Common Gang dismantles Old Misery’s house. A character created by this author founds a plastics company after being inspired by York Harding’s argument for a “Third Force.” In a novel by this author of “The Destructors,” a yellow-eyed Mestizo meets the protagonist when he is on the run from an anti-clerical lieutenant. For 10 points, name this author of The Quiet American and The Power and the Glory. ","answer":"ANSWER: Graham Greene <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"5. This family’s arrangements with the Bishop of Brixen nearly bankrupted them when the bishop died. This family promoted guaiacum (“GWAI-uh-kum”) as a cure for syphilis because this family shipped guaiacum wood from Hispaniola. Due to the namesake flowers appearing on their coat-of-arms, one branch of this family was known as “[this family] of the Lily.” Three daily prayers were accepted in lieu of rent at a collection of yellow buildings that are named for this family. This family contributed over one thousand kilograms of gold to ensure Charles V’s election as Holy Roman Emperor. A member of this Augsburg family bought the rights to silver mines in Tirol and controlled a European copper monopoly. For 10 points, name this German banking family led by Jakob (“YAH-kop”) the Rich. ","answer":"ANSWER: the Fugger (“FOOG-guh”) family [accept Jakob Fugger the Rich] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"6. L.A. Times journalist Amy Kaufman wrote a 2018 New York Times best-selling book partly titled for this show that begins by examining its creation by Mike Fleiss. In one scene in this show, a woman refuses to use the phrase “cleaning lady” to refer to her “nanny” Raquel. In 2019, a spinoff of this show featured a landmark same-sex relationship between Kristian Haggerty and Demi Burnett, who was originally in love with a man who jumps a fence in one episode. Corinne Olympios was involved in a sexual assault scandal that temporarily suspended production of a spinoff of this show that is set “in Paradise.” Cassie Randolph was chosen as the winner of its 23rd season by Colton Underwood. Chris Harrison hosts, for 10 points, what romantic reality television show? ","answer":"ANSWER: The Bachelor [accept Bachelor Nation; accept Bachelor in Paradise] <Pop Culture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"7. Satirical versions of this animal were depicted with magpies in minhwa folk art. A flower-plucking rishi has the legs of this animal, which Budhi Pallien can shapeshift into. A painter who drew an animal that was part-horse, part-this animal inspired a Chinese saying meaning “mediocre” or “so-so.” In a Jātaka tale, a jackal tricks this animal into going back in a cage to aid a Brahmin. After this animal gives up waiting to become human in a cave, the bear-woman Ungnyeo (“oong-nyuh”) marries Hwanung (“HWAH-noong”) and gives birth to King Dangun (“DAHN-goon”). To feed this animal, Prince Sattva sacrifices himself. This brave, competitive zodiac animal only gets third in the Great Race despite its strength and represents the West when it’s shown with white fur. For 10 points, what animal is depicted as Shere Khan (“sheer con”) in the Jungle Book? ","answer":"ANSWER: tigers [or tigresses; or lǎohǔ; or fu; or holang-i or horangi; accept sher until read; or baagh; or vyaghra; prompt on big cats or felines or other nonspecific answers] <Mythology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"8. A drawing of a grain of wheat is at the center of one of the diagrams of this author’s work that Józef Czapski made for lectures on this author that he delivered in a Soviet prison camp. Eric Karpeles wrote a companion to this writer’s allusions to art, such as the nickname “Giotto’s Charity” that is given to a kitchen-maid or the description of a woman resembling Botticelli’s Zipporah. A character created by this author associates his beloved with a “little phrase” in a violin sonata. This author’s magnum opus was retitled after a phrase from Shakespeare’s Sonnet 30 in the original English translation by C. K. Scott Moncrief. For 10 points, memories of Combray are brought back by the taste of a tea-soaked madeleine in Swann’s Way, the first part of what French author’s In Search of Lost Time? ","answer":"ANSWER: Marcel Proust [accept Valentin Louis Georges Eugène Marcel Proust] <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"9. Heating up isotoluene causes it to isomerize by a reaction discovered by this man. This man discovered a reaction in which a bond migration and a 1,5-hydrogen shift occurs between an alkene with an allylic hydrogen and a compound with a multiple bond. This discoverer of the ene reaction is the second namesake of a reaction by which [4]-annulene dimerizes. This man is the second namesake of a reaction involving a suprafacial interaction between a four pi electron system and a two pi electron system, and proceeds through an endo transition state. This man is the second namesake of reaction that forms cyclohexene derivatives from dienes and dienophiles. For 10 points, name this scientist who names a reaction with Otto Diels. ","answer":"ANSWER: Kurt Alder <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"9. The priest Albert Lacombe persuaded Crowfoot to accept this industry in the Blackfoot Nation. James Ross headed an engineering project in this industry with a memorial at Craigellachie (“cray-GHEL-uh-kee”). The discovery that a magnate of this industry, Hugh Allan, had secretly funded the Conservative Party allowed Alexander Mackenzie’s liberals to come to power. Sandford Fleming worked in this industry, which inspired him to develop the idea of time zones. Bribes paid by this industry to officials in John MacDonald’s government resulted in the Pacific Scandal. For 10 points, name this industry that enabled transcontinental travel over land in the 19th century. ","answer":"ANSWER: Canadian railroad industry [or railway industry; or train industry; prompt on transportation industry] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"1. Stephen Dale’s theory of an architectural style named for this phenomenon is discussed in a Sebastian Prange book titled for this type of Islam. The reconstructed terms “habaRat” and “timuR” are thought to refer to a directional axis based on this phenomenon in Proto-Austronesian. The practice of kharif coincides with this phenomenon, while the practice of rabi follows it. Ahmad ibn Mājid is apocryphally credited with helping Vasco de Gama use this phenomenon, which Gama nonetheless struggled against on his return from Calicut. This phenomenon dictated trade cycles on the Indian Ocean by forcing mariners to travel northeast in the summer. The Tonlé Sap River reverses due to, for 10 points, what wind system that brings rain to Southeast Asia? ","answer":"ANSWER: monsoons [or monsoon season; prompt on wind, rain, wet season, or rainy season] <World History> Bonuses "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this city captured by Scipio Africanus in 209 BC. Scipio was aided in that effort by a storm that drained the lagoon surrounding this city, allowing him to attack its undefended north. ","answer":"ANSWER: Carthago Nova [or New Carthage; or Cartagena; do not accept or prompt on “Carthago” or “Carthage”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Carthago Nova was founded by this man’s son-in-law Hasdrubal, who shared a name with a son of this man killed at the Metaurus. Livy wrote that this man made another son dip his hands in blood and swear perpetual hostility to Rome. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hamilcar Barca [prompt on Barca] (The son is Hannibal.) "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Diocletian designated Carthago Nova as the capital of the Carthaginensis province in this region. A folk etymology connects this peninsula’s city of Barcelona with its supposed founding by Hamilcar Barca. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hispania [or the Iberian Peninsula; or Spain] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this position in the philosophy of mind that states that the hard problem of consciousness cannot be solved by humans. This position is championed by Colin McGinn. ","answer":"ANSWER: New Mysterianism (The position is named after the band “? and the Mysterians.”) "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Philosophers of mind often use these theoretical entities in thought experiments to test intuitions about consciousness. These entities are indistinguishable from humans but lack qualia or sentience. ","answer":"ANSWER: philosophical zombies [accept p-zombies] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Contemporary debate about the metaphysics of consciousness boils down to pitting materialism versus this position, which states that the conscious mind is non-physical in some sense. Descartes is closely associated with the mind-body form of this position. ","answer":"ANSWER: dualism [accept mind-body dualism] <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name or describe this section that notes how, of the 155 chapters of the novel it appears in, the last 99 chapters are “expendable.” It advises the reader to read the novel’s chapters in various different orders and combinations. ","answer":"ANSWER: “Table of Instructions” [accept “Tablero de dirección”; accept descriptions such as the introduction or beginning or author’s note or prologue of Hopscotch or Rayuela; do not accept any answers indicating that this section is the first chapter] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] The “Table of Instructions” opens Hopscotch, which is a novel by this author who also wrote short stories such as “Blow-Up” and “Axolotl.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Julio Cortázar "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] The “Table of Instructions” often leads readers into skipping chapters told from the perspective of this mysterious writer, who is theorized to be the true author of Hopscotch within the narrative. This writer uniquely titles several chapters in Hopscotch, including one that is supposedly “Written by [him] in the hospital.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Morelli [accept Morelliana] <World/Other Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"4. Name some things about the hottest song of 2019, “Baby Shark,” for 10 points each. [10] “Baby Shark” became the unofficial anthem of the Nationals, whose reliever Sean Doolittle was praised for his explanation of why he refused to do this action. The Golden State Warriors’ invitation to take this action was revoked after rumors that Steph Curry would not participate. ","answer":"ANSWER: visiting the White House [accept equivalents; prompt on answers like visiting Trump or visiting the President by asking “where?”] [10] “Baby Shark” has also become popular at Lebanese protests, which were sparked in part by a tax on this platform. India launched a fact-checking program for this platform after it provoked several lynchings. "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Jess Phillips, a politician from this city, launched a crowdfunding campaign to protest planned school cuts using “Baby Shark.” This city’s large Muslim minority has launched protests against LGBT-inclusive education, leading to a controversial ban on holding such protests near school grounds. ","answer":"ANSWER: Birmingham [accept Birmingham Yardley] <Current Events> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this type of scale. In musicology, a hemitonic version of this scale called the in scale is often contrasted with an anhemitonic version of it called the yo scale. ","answer":"ANSWER: pentatonic scale [accept major pentatonic scale; accept hemitonic or anhemitonic pentatonic scale] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Many East Asian folk songs are built on the pentatonic scale, such as this Korean folk song. In 1896, after hearing three Korean students singing this song, anthropologist Alice Fletcher made the oldest extant recording of it. ","answer":"ANSWER: “Arirang” (“ah-ree-rahng”) [accept Arirang Mass Games (Festival) or Arirang chukje] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Another Korean folk music tradition, pansori, usually involves a singer performing with a player of the buk, which is a Korean variety of this instrument. Other types of this instrument include the djembe (“JEM-bay”) and the bongos. ","answer":"ANSWER: drums [prompt on percussion instruments] <Classical Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name or describe this essay published in Periodical Discourse, which Porfiry Petrovich questions the protagonist about because it suggests that “extraordinary” people have the right to “transgress the law.” ","answer":"ANSWER: “On Crime” [accept equivalents such as the article written by Rodion Raskolnikov or Rodion Raskolnikov’s article about crime; prompt on the article from Crime and Punishment by asking “by who?”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] The article “On Crime” lays out the ideas that motivate Raskolnikov’s murder of an elderly pawnbroker in Crime and Punishment, a novel by this Russian author. ","answer":"ANSWER: Fyodor Dostoevsky "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] During their discussion of “On Crime,” Porfiry asks Raskolnikov if he believes in this story. In Part IV, Raskolnikov forces Sonya to read him this story, which he’s later reminded of by a book under his pillow before turning himself in. ","answer":"ANSWER: the raising of Lazarus [or equivalents of Jesus raising Lazarus from the dead; prompt on the Bible, the New Testament, or the Gospel of John] <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this quantum algorithm that performs a search in “big-O of the square root of n” time. ","answer":"ANSWER: Grover’s algorithm "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Without quantum computing, this is the runtime required to perform a sequential search. Give your answer using big-O notation in terms of n, the number of entries in the set. ","answer":"ANSWER: big-O of n [or linear time] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] To prepare for quantum-based threats to its namesake cloud, IBM is developing a suite called CRYSTALS that implements this general form of cryptography. Encryption in this scheme is based on solving the “shortest vector problem.” ","answer":"ANSWER: lattice-based cryptography <Other Science (Computer Science)> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Gaius Mucius Scaevola (“gai-oos mu-kee-oos SKY-voh-lah”) proved his bravery in this profession by sticking his hand in a fire. Cloelia swam across the Tiber and Horatius Cocles remained on a collapsing bridge to assist men with this profession campaigning against Lars Porsena of Clusium. ","answer":"ANSWER: soldiers [or milites or miles; accept any equivalents like military or infantry] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Veturia became a model Roman matron when she refused to help this son of hers rebel against Rome, consigning him to death at the hands of the Volscians. In a play about this general, his mother is renamed Volumnia. ","answer":"ANSWER: Gaius Marcius Coriolanus [accept The Tragedy of Coriolanus (by Shakespeare)] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] After the lustful decemvir (“dih-SEM-ver”) Appius Claudius tried to abduct this woman by claiming that she was his slave, her father stabbed her to preserve her chastity. Like Lucretia, this woman inspired a Botticelli furniture painting intended for a bridal chamber. ","answer":"ANSWER: Verginia [or Virginia; accept The Story of Virginia or The Stories of Virginia or Le Storie di Virginia] <Mythology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this ship where Armistead’s owner President John Tyler escaped injury from an explosion. Captain Robert Stockton’s faulty Peacemaker cannon caused the explosion during a Potomac River cruise. ","answer":"ANSWER: USS Princeton "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] John Ericsson, the designer of the USS Princeton, pioneered the design of these ships. Ericsson built the USS Monitor, which fought the CSS Merrimack in the first duel between these armored ships. ","answer":"ANSWER: ironclads [or ironclad warships] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] During the Mexican-American War, Stockton developed a rivalry with this general over who had authority over California. Kit Carson’s shoeless trek allowed Stockton to send reinforcements in time to save this general at San Pasqual. ","answer":"ANSWER: Stephen W. Kearny <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this metal that forms a diatomic polycation with a charge of 2+, which is the cation in calomel. It is toxic and liquid at room temperature. ","answer":"ANSWER: mercury [or Hg] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] An electrode made of calomel was formerly a commonly used reference in this group of electroanalytical techniques that comes in “linear sweep” and “cyclic” forms. In it, the current generated by a redox reaction is measured as electric potential is changed. ","answer":"ANSWER: voltammetry [accept linear sweep voltammetry; accept cyclic voltammetry; prompt on LSV or CV by asking “what does that stand for?”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] The calomel electrode has mostly been replaced by this reference electrode due to its toxicity. It produces a potential of about 198 millivolts with respect to the standard hydrogen electrode when used in a saturated solution of potassium chloride. ","answer":"ANSWER: silver chloride electrode [or AgCl electrode] <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this novel whose main story alternates with “intercalary” chapters, such as one describing a turtle crawling across a highway. In the following chapter, Tom encounters a preacher sitting under a willow tree. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Grapes of Wrath "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] One of the “intercalary” chapters of John Steinbeck’s The Grapes of Wrath describes the beauty of springtime in this state, where “Okies” such as the Joad family travel to find work in the novel. ","answer":"ANSWER: California "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Another of the interchapters is set in one of these places, where Mae gives peppermint candy canes to two migrant children who visit it. Richard Russo’s Empire Falls centers on Miles Roby, the owner of one of these places. ","answer":"ANSWER: diners [or restaurants; or grills; accept greasy spoons or other equivalents] <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this controversial proposed language family first described by Joseph Greenberg. This macrofamily would encompass all languages of the Western Hemisphere not found in the Eskimo–Aleut or Na-Dene (“NAH den-AY”) families. ","answer":"ANSWER: Amerind language family [prompt on American Indian languages; prompt on Native American languages] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] The most widely spoken of the Na-Dene languages is this Southern Athabaskan language spoken widely in the Four Corners region of the American Southwest. This tonal language is closely related to Apache. ","answer":"ANSWER: Navajo language [or Navaho language; accept Diné bizaad] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] A 2008 proposal called for a merging of the Na-Dene languages of North America with the Yeniseian languages of this geographical region into a single language family. The word shaman originates from the Northern Tungusic (“tun-GOO-sick”) languages of this region. ","answer":"ANSWER: Siberia [or Sibír; prompt on Asia; prompt on Russia] <Social Science (Anthropology)> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this kingdom whose port of Óc Eo (“oke ow”) has been identified with Ptolemy’s description of Kattigara. This kingdom eventually fell to its vassal Chenla. ","answer":"ANSWER: Funan "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] The Khmer of Funan transmitted Hinduism to this coastal Vietnamese kingdom around the 4th century. A fast-growing drought-resistant strain of rice is named for this kingdom, which built a large temple complex at Mỹ Sơn (“mee sun”). ","answer":"ANSWER: Champa [accept Champa rice] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Khmer barays (“ba-RYES”) in this capital of Jayavarman II might have represented Hindu cosmological symbols. The large wat complex named for this Khmer capital represents the mythical Mount Meru. ","answer":"ANSWER: Angkor [or Angkor Wat; or Angkor Thom] <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this text often illustrated by medieval Spanish artists to accompany Beatus of Liébana’s commentary on it. Those illustrations depict figures like the Four Horsemen from this apocalyptic book of the Bible. ","answer":"ANSWER: Book of Revelation [do not accept or prompt on “Revelations”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] The bold primary colors of the paintings in the Beatus codices (“KO-dih-seez”) exemplify this art style, the complement of the Mudéjar (“moo-DEH-zhar”) style. This term denotes the Islamic-art-influenced work produced by Iberian Christians. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mozarabic [or repoblación art; or repopulation art] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Meyer Schapiro also exposed this artist to the Morgan Beatus, likely influencing his “sectionals” paintings. The paintings that this artist created for the Four Seasons Restaurant in the Seagram Building were never installed. ","answer":"ANSWER: Mark Rothko <Painting/Sculpture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this avant-garde Japanese style of dance pioneered after World War II by Tatsumi Hijikata and Kazuo Ohno. This style involves ultra-slow movement, white makeup, and macabre or taboo subject matter. ","answer":"ANSWER: butoh [or butō] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Kourlas goes on to compare Phoenix’s movements in Joker to that of Sergei Polunin and this other Russian dancer. This man often danced with Margot Fonteyn (“MAR-go fon-TAIN”) during his time at Frederick Ashton’s Royal Ballet. ","answer":"ANSWER: Rudolf Nureyev "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Kourlas argues for the centrality of dance to Arthur’s life by noting that Shall We Dance, a 1937 film starring this versatile dancer, is playing at his mother’s apartment. This man starred in films like Top Hat and Swing Time alongside Ginger Rogers. ","answer":"ANSWER: Fred Astaire <Other Arts (Dance)> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Identify these molecules that include a 16-carbon long “palmitic” one. Three of these molecules are attached to a glycerol to form triglycerides. ","answer":"ANSWER: fatty acids [prompt on carboxylic acids; prompt on palmitic acids; prompt on lipids] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] With the exception of very-long-chain fatty acids, fatty acids are broken down in this organelle during beta-oxidation. The process of ketogenesis also primarily occurs in this organelle. ","answer":"ANSWER: mitochondrion [or mitochondria] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] The beta-oxidation of fatty acids with this property produces a propionyl-CoA end product, which then undergoes a vitamin-B12-dependent conversion to succinyl-CoA. ","answer":"ANSWER: odd-chain fatty acids [or equivalent answers like “the fatty acids have an odd number of carbons”] <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Virginia Woolf wrote an essay about “Thoughts of Peace” during what sort of wartime event? The Lion, The Witch, and The Wardrobe begins with the Pevensie (“PEV-en-see”) children being evacuated from London due to these events. ","answer":"ANSWER: air raid [or bombing raids; or aerial attacks; or airstrikes; or the Blitz; or equivalents] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] The last paragraph of “Thoughts of Peace in an Air Raid” quotes the phrase “The huntsmen are up in America” from this author’s treatise on the quincunx. Woolf praised this “greatest physician in Norwich” in her essay “The Elizabethan Lumber Room.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Thomas Browne (The treatise is The Garden of Cyrus.) "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] The protagonist sits down to read one of Browne’s “longest and most marvellously contorted cogitations” in this Virginia Woolf “biography,” whose title character is modeled on her lover Vita Sackville-West. ","answer":"ANSWER: Orlando <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] The Austrophilic diplomat Alexey Bestuzhev advised this monarch, whose death during the Seven Years’ War was termed the “Miracle of the House of Brandenburg.” Natalia Lopukhina had her tongue torn off by this empress after being framed for a plot to restore her predecessor Ivan VI (“the sixth”). ","answer":"ANSWER: Empress Elizabeth of Russia [or Elizabeth Petrovna; or Yelisaveta; or Elizaveta] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Alexey’s father Pyotr Bestuzhev effectively governed this duchy on behalf of Anna of Russia. Duke Jacob Kettler sent settlers from this duchy to colonize The Gambia and Tobago. ","answer":"ANSWER: Duchy of Courland and Semigallia "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Alexander Bestuzhev edited the Polar Star, a journal of this movement named for a month. Nicholas I crushed this revolt of constitutionalist officers who rose up after his elder brother Constantine gave up the throne. ","answer":"ANSWER: Decembrist Revolt [or Decembrist Uprising] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this practice that is prescribed for regions deemed ‘awrah. Women who partake in this practice may wear a dupatta, chador, burqa, or ḥijāb, since most Muslim scholars consider the niqāb excessive. ","answer":"ANSWER: covering parts of the body [accept equivalents such as wearing clothing over body parts; accept covering specific body parts such as hair or head; prompt on purdah] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Members of this Islamic sect may avoid strictly covering their bodies by pointing to verse 256 of Surah Al-Baqarah, which claims “there is no compulsion in religion.” This sect, which originated in Punjab and is now based in London, holds that Jesus was buried in the Roza Bal Shrine in Kashmir. ","answer":"ANSWER: Ahmadi Muslims [or Ahmadiyya Muslim Community; or Ahmadiyya Muslim Jama‘at; or al-Jamā‘ah al-Islāmīyah al-Aḥmadīyah; accept the pejorative term Qadiani] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Ahmadi Muslims pledge to follow “ten conditions” in a ceremony known by this Arabic term, which refers to initiations or oaths of allegiance. The Qur’an describes this type of ritual with the pledge of Ridwan under a tree before the Treaty of Ḥudaybiyyah (“hoo-die-BEE-yeh”). ","answer":"ANSWER: bay‘ah [or bai‘at] <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this author of the treatise Mecanique analytique whose reformulation of classical mechanics relies on the function “L equals T minus V.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Joseph-Louis Lagrange [or Giuseppe Luigi Lagrangia; or Giuseppe Ludivico de la Grange Tournier; accept Lagrangian] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Performing an involution named for this scientist on the Lagrangian allows for the derivation of the Hamiltonian formulation of mechanics. He also names a symbol useful when working with quadratic residues. ","answer":"ANSWER: Adrien-Marie Legendre (“luh-ZHOND”) [accept Legendre symbol] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] In Hamiltonian mechanics, the phase space is this type of manifold, which can be described as a smooth manifold M with a closed, non-degenerate differential 2-form omega. ","answer":"ANSWER: symplectic manifold <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Name this D minor concerto. It begins with the strings alternating between the eighth notes F and A before the soloist enters with the melody G, A, low D. ","answer":"ANSWER: Violin Concerto in D minor by Jean Sibelius [or Sibelius VC; prompt on partial answers] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] The Violin Concerto in D minor was the only concerto composed by Jean Sibelius (“zhahn sih-BAY-lee-us”), who was from this country. Sibelius also composed an 1899 nationalistic tone poem partly named for this country. ","answer":"ANSWER: Finland [accept Finlandia] "},{"tournament":"ACF Regionals 2020","difficulty":"Difficulty: Moderate College","round":"L","question":"[10] Due to its rhythmically challenging and energetic nature, the third movement of Sibelius’s Violin Concerto was referred to as a “polonaise for polar bears” by this early 20th-century British musicologist in his Essays in Musical Analysis. ","answer":"ANSWER: Donald Tovey [or Sir Donald Francis Tovey] <Classical Music>"}]
